Perfect. Okay, I guess we can slowly get
started then. Um, good morning if you
are you're in the same time zone as us
or good afternoon or wherever you are.
Uh, this is the office hours call for
your go May 2025. Uh, my name is
Alexander with me. I have Maria, Yonas,
and Freddy. Uh, and yeah, I'll just go
through some of the latest things we've
done in in Go in this month and then few
announcements and then we'll get to the
Q&A. That's basically what this last set
of. So, uh, what's new go for GitHub?
Uh, if you're ever in doubt, you can
always go to
AKMS/AGO release notes and you can find
the latest things. Um, if you go there
right now, you'll find the these three
things. Uh, I'll go through each of them
briefly individually, but you can always
go to you can go to the release notes
and and read more and figure out how to
enable these things in your
repos. So, starting off with input
validation. Um, I mean, of course, we've
always had validation of inputs into
workflows, but we've enhanced that in
the in the latest preview. Um, so now
what we saw was that when you ran the
create release workflow, if you set the
update version number parameter to
something that al goes doesn't accept,
then it would do a bunch of things and
then it would fail at the end and that's
obviously not ideal. So we enhanced this
experience a bit to make it fail earlier
so you don't end up with some release
that you can't really use for anything.
Um, and the same thing has been done for
increment version number and it's
something we'll slowly improve on. um
over time. Uh so basically in the future
you'll expect your ALGO workflows to
fail early uh if there are any issues
with the inputs that you give the
workflows, but for now it's only the
create release and increment version
number
workflows. The second thing we've rolled
out, this is something you'll see when
you run up the video system files. U if
you're on preview, you might already see
it. Otherwise, you'll have to wait for
the 7.2 two I believe is the next
version. Uh but at the top of your ALGO
file, you get this schema property. And
the schema property will do two things
for you. First of all, when you go into
your ALGO settings file, you'll now get
like these suggestions from VS Code as
you can see and you can start typing and
it'll filter and you can get a
description of the different settings
and a link to where you can go read
more. U so this kind of enhances your
experience, you know, editing ilog
settings.
Um, another place we're going to use
this is, uh, within the workflows, we'll
also validate whether your settings
match the schema. Uh, this is really
just to ensure that you've set up your
settings correctly and, you know, your
settings are applied in the way that
algo expects it to be, right? That it's
living up to the syntax of ALGO
settings. Uh, so we'll validate your
settings against the schema and if it
doesn't match, uh, we'll show uh, a
warning.
And finally uh we rolled out a feature
for failing pull requests or new
warnings. This was a feedback we got
from some partners that they want to
fail pull request whenever a pull
request intro is introducing a new
warning. Oh, I'm getting someone saying
my screen is not visible.
You see the top
one?
Oh, okay. Um, yes. So, this new feature
failing pull requests on your warnings.
Um, so it won't change the behavior of
your CI/CD workflows. Uh, that'll still
fail on the same errors as it used to.
But now when you open up a pull request
and if your pull request introduces a
new code cup warning, um, it'll fail and
you'll you'll be forced to uh uh to fix
that before you merge your
PR. So those were the three things we've
added to ALGO in the last month. Right
now it's in preview. Uh I don't know if
we have any. We'll ship 7.2 soon. Like
we'll just need to yeah have it for a
little while and then when we feel ready
we'll ship to
7.2. Uh on before we go to the Q&A, just
a couple of announcements. This one is a
copy from last month. Um, but just in
case some of you haven't run into this
yet, um, PC container helper versions
earlier than se 6.1 uh, basically don't
really work anymore.
Um, algo repositories are not affected.
But of course, if you're used to
spinning up local containers and stuff,
uh, you you will be affected. Uh, so if
you haven't done that in a while, maybe
check that. Uh, yeah, you're running a
container version higher than 6.1.
One other announcement is uh please make
sure you regularly update
your run update algo system files uh
because some of the earlier versions of
a go will soon stop working. 5.0 and
lower sorry 5.0 will work lower than 5.0
will not
work. Uh for reference 5.0 is about a
year old now. So if you haven't run
updated grow system files in a year,
please make sure you run it uh
relatively
soon. And with that, I will kick off the
Q&A. I'm Freddy also just joined me in
the office
now. Uh please use the Q&A tab instead
of the chat
tab if you have any questions.
You want to say anything?
Actually, maybe before we get to the
Q&A, we can uh I can say one I can talk
to Tiff to
uh just came into in the door. So
um yeah, you probably heard about uh or
maybe you saw my LinkedIn
post that I am no longer with Microsoft
or I'm still here uh at least for for
for some time being. Um but I'm like no
longer
um part of this team. what I've promised
uh Alexander, Maria, Sebastian, and
Jonas to do is to be here for the
foreseeable future and uh and make sure
that that that the transition period is
not like I'm not trying to like go
through everything in two two days or
two weeks to to like uh but but we'll
like extend that period for for some
time. So, so that'll be a a good chance
of of the transition period to be smooth
and and I don't foresee any any huge I
mean obviously there's going to be a
huge missing me but uh but I think the
team is more than capable of of taking
over and uh making sure that algo will
have a bright future and I'll do my
utmost to make sure that the transition
period is as as smooth as possible.
So it wasn't my decision. It wasn't the
people in Lug's decision. I think my
name was picked out from a computer
somewhere in Redmond and then it was my
turn to leave. So that's how it feels
and that's how I chose to interpret it
which is the reason why I mean we're
still alone with good friends and uh no
bad feelings.
So who will take over from Freddy? Well,
there's a
team like you've seen. Alexander, Maria,
Jonas, and Sebastian are the four people
working on a go for GitHub. Container
helper is probably going to be mostly
Sebastian in a second. Alexander as I
can see on the different pull request
and stuff like that. Um, but
yeah, it won't be left. I mean, well,
we've been working with Freddy for the
last two years or something. Yeah. So, I
mean, we have some experience now, but
of course, not any anywhere near what
Freddy has, but uh we'll we'll pick it
up from there. And of course, it'll be a
learning process for us as
well. Okay. So, there's a question here
about uh the fail pull request new
warnings. Can it be switched on or off
with the setting? And yes, it can.
Uh I didn't mention that, but uh if you
go to go release notes, you'll see the
the setting and a description how to
enable it.
First question we got was our
development relies heavily on onrem
docker containers. Now bc container
helper is deprecated. What will be the
future of onrem container building? How
can we prepare it to be
ready? Uh yes mean so busy container
upper is not deprecated yet. It's
deprecated in about two years time I
believe is scheduled. um and and it is
being replaced by a new module. So I
don't think our plan is to leave you
just you know by yourself. Uh we are
planning to replace some of the
functionality maybe not all of it but
certainly I mean the core development
functionalities we're planning on to
replace. Yeah, I think the plan was
always to say the stuff that's used for
running local containers will be in a
different module. All the stuff that's
used for running
DevOps stuff is no not no longer going
to be in a PowerShell module like that.
is going to be in various modules where
the release vehicle is a go and if
people want to use those things they're
like they'll be yeah they'll be
experiencing more changes because when
the release vehicle is a go we'll do the
changes that are necessary for a go but
not look whether you're breaking anybody
there
so I think that's still the
Lots of questions.
Just want to say thanks Freddy. You did
an awesome job for the pipeline store in
the whole BC ecosystem. We will be
missed. Definitely. Thank you.
Can you give us an estimate in the
famous PR for indirect templates?
Hoping to do it this month. um on this
month. Yeah, May,
June.
So, let's see. I think the B has done
more up to the people having time to
actually do review and stuff like that.
So, yeah, it's in review and we just
need to get it in as soon as possible.
So, no, it'll go will be supported for
years to come.
Uh I mean it will be supported in the
years to come. Um I didn't mention this
but there's also if you go to Yammer
there's a Microsoft announcement from
Dimmitri uh one of the PMs here about
you know the future of ILGO and stuff
and it it is something we're continuing
to invest
in. I need to build artifacts and
releases for older BC version. Is there
some documentation for this
case to
build? Do you build an app for all the
VC
versions? You probably have
to create a container for that version
and then yeah build it with that.
You can if you want to build it in the
pipeline, you need to use the functions
for that. If you want to build it in VS
Code, you can download the probably the
VS code extension from the container
that you built with your own artifacts
and you can create like install that in
your VS code and and build with that.
It's cumbersome. It's not something
we mean we recommend everybody to be on
the latest and greatest always, right?
But um it can be
done documentation probably not
something might find stuff on my blog
very old posts on how to do some of
these things but uh
yeah would know when the page scripting
feature in SAS is expected to be
released. I don't know maybe I didn't it
already released or maybe I have the
wrong understanding. We're not running
we are unable to run page scripting
tests on SAS environments due to
the to the 2FA or MFA requirement of SAS
currently but it is being worked on. So
that's going to be yeah it's Sebastian
that's working on that piece. Whether
it's going to be next month or months
after that, I don't know.
But soon as
possible. See, it's gone into some
section. Give it a second.
I think the sharing has stopped. Yeah,
it's just
uh it was sharing my screen over and
over again,
but trying to find a pop
out. Maybe not.
We're still
here. Even though the screen is going a
bit on
a some
chats
Jose
Madreal
K asks, "So my name is not Frederick,
I'm Freddy, but yes, I'll be in ML
September." So, I promised
uh Roberto Corella something and I'll
obviously keep my promises. I'm a man of
my word. So, yes, I'll be there.
Yeah. Not next September, this
September. So, I had promised one of our
MVPs that had run a a algo onboarding
course if he could find 20 partners in
Spain to uh to do that, I'll do it a
full day course. and he found 20
partners and I obviously will yeah do
that.
Thanks for all the hard work, late
nights and friendship over the last
years. I've learned a lot from you.
Thank you, Ryan.
I receive an error on the publish
artifacts pipeline step. Failed to
create artifact. Artifact storage quota
has been hit. Unable to upload any new
artifacts. Usage is recalculated every 6
to 12 hours. Can the publish artifact
step be turned off in this case?
Uh, no. I don't believe it can. Okay.
So, what school are you running on on
GitHub? Is that a free account or is it
the pro or what Christian?
Um I don't think we
can we have some settings for retention,
right? Yeah, there's some longlasting
and short lasting artifacts. Do we have
some settings to define how long keep
the artifacts for? Team
team I think you should create an issue
on that
then you should investigate how much FL
there is. I thought that would be
bigger and also like give
some advice in
Is this like very large apps or is it
Yeah, you can mention stuff like that
is or is it like a lot of
builds? What's what's causing
this?
Yes. Uh I have another question
regarding the feature fail and new
warnings. Is there a threshold value
where I can configure something like
below X warnings I'm fine but only stop
if it's more than X
warnings Yonas do you want to respond to
this
one? Yeah. So no, we don't have any of
those settings at the moment. The
uh this feature essentially looks at new
warnings only. So if you have a codebase
that already has a bunch of warnings and
you want to block new warnings from
getting in without having to fix all of
the current warnings, this is the type
of feature you want to enable. Other
than that, there are other ways to
control breaking and failing on
warnings, but not um threshold that is
configurable in terms of the number of
warnings etc.
I'm new to Yogo. I need to start from
basic. Any links you can share? I
believe some links were shared.
Hopefully that's
helpful. Can I join that? Guessing maybe
it's the Madrid thing that's being
mentioned here. Or so Ryan, I'm going to
hold the entire course in Spanish. So
capable of Oh, no. I'm not is in
English. You have to talk to Roberto
Cora, one of our MVPs in Spain.
He's the host. I'm just a guest
speaker. What is the recommended
approach for using Azure DevOps work
item planning together with
ALGO? Um, I don't think we have anything
documented on this. Um but it is
something we do within Microsoft. So we
have a couple of you'll go GitHub
repositories but all of our work it
automatically is in Azure DevOps and I
mean it's not a painless experience. Uh
but there there are some kind of
integrations that you can use uh the
Azure boards integration being one of
them. Uh so you can reference work items
from GitHub and it creates automatically
creates a link between the two and so
on. That's something that kind of eases
the experience. Maybe that's something
we should document at some point. Uh I
feel like I've heard this before. Uh
I've gotten this question before around
how do you integrate Azure DevOps and
GitHub.
Um yeah that's the tool we use and then
we build some own automation to you know
do some other syncing uh but that might
not be necessary for your your use
case. We're currently facing
difficulties comparing two different BC
versions in A Go 26 and 25. Manually
checking each a file is proving to be
quite
challenging. EC
maybe you could try rephrasing the
question or something and then we'll we
can come back to this one. What do you
mean about BC versions? There are two
different branches where development has
gone in two directions.
What are you talking about
here? We'll see if we can come back to
this
one. We're currently in the process of
evaluating whether we want to switch
from Azure DevOps to GitHub with ALGO.
What is the general recommendation here?
Is ADO the future or GitHub?
I don't think
we let's see we and Microsoft I don't
think Microsoft does any recommendation
on ADO or GitHub. Uh I think both are
supported. If you look at the teams I
don't think there's any doubt that
GitHub receives the most love and
attention from development teams. A lot
of features comes to GitHub. Not not so
much on DevOps. Uh but as a devops has
like an advantage of of some areas on
some areas where they have more
featurerich functionality already and
GitHub is catching up on that. So it
kind of depends on where you you have a
lot of investments on ADO and you need
to stay there. Our recommendation is to
use a managed solution so you don't get
stuck in this okay now container help is
no longer supported and you have to like
figure out where you get the
functionality in that one from
um and you can stay on ADO if you use
alops alaka u that our recommendation
will be
github or my s recommendation server
Uh also I am not sure if this is the
right platform to ask this question but
I'm also interested in datadriven
testing but I'm not sure about the data
templates to load the data. I need help
here as well. I asked the query on
Yammer. Did not get any response yet.
I don't think Go has any support for any
datadriven testing yet. Uh I got the
question on the last uh
uh a meeting I had in where was that?
Was that
directions North America? I think it
was. Yeah. where one of the MVPs talked
about the new datadriven the AI test
toolkit that was able to do datadriven
test testing. Um we haven't built
support for that into a go yet. That's
something that needs to be investigated
and and how we can do that in the best
way.
There anything in the
chats? Is there any such GitHub copilot
agent in VS Code for refining the code
with the base code of BC with our custom
extension for fixing the
errors? question. I
don't guess there is a co-pilot uh code
review, but it's not very good
at AL yet. But
that's would be something
that should be worked on in order to
make the co the co-pilot code reviewer
capable of doing actual code reviews and
formatting and stuff like that. Maybe
even stuff like uh pre-commit could be
extended to be able to
format a code. I don't know. Um code cut
can do some of these things I guess.
Got a guy outside here trying to hammer
his way through a window, I guess.
But hope it's not too noisy.
building runtime packages supported by
ALGO the answer that is no right yeah
never never got to that it's part of the
backlog yes can we submit an idea for
code formatting and code review on
pulest or by AI
Even better, Ryan, you can create a pull
request to add the functionality to it.
How about
that? On the ELGO project board, there
are some cards about auto translation.
Is there any news on that?
I don't believe so.
in the background.
Auto translation.
Yeah, I was going to say I feel like I
remember having a discussion around
translations at a round table at
directions, but uh I don't think we
really touched the whole translation
story since then unfortunately.
Yeah, I think the biggest feature that
came out of that round table was the
incremental builds
feature
23 that was in that was that round table
stand it was last who suggested it.
H
maybe 24 was I was in what was it?
You seem to remember having some
translation
discussion but no sadly not something
we've
uh had the time to to work on.
We still have another what 25 minutes
left for for questions. Uh feel free to
post them in the Q&A. You can also just
you have a suggestion for a feature or a
general comment or something by all
means let us know. It's a good forum for
us to get feedback as well and like
understand what areas of the go we're
lacking and features you're missing and
so
on like translations clearly.
You can ask people so if they raise
their hand and see how many people
actually would
uh missing features like
that. So how many
people would be like interested in
translations built into pipelines and
stuff like that? Is
that two three four?
That's a lot.
Okay. Seems like it
this this is maybe a good opportunity to
also promote a little bit the
discussions we have on GitHub where we
have ideas tab. So maybe someone can
create this idea and people can upload
it. This is I think now I know we kind
of like change the way we work a little
bit. Uh but the idea going forward is
that we're going to use um this place to
Yeah, thank you Alex for sharing it. Uh
the idea is sections to kind of u
evaluate new
features in our backlog.
Yes. And when you go in also have a look
if you see the idea already and you can
vote or upvote it. That also helps us
understand how impactful it
is. Yeah. If you go under discussions
and click view under ideas,
then it's a good place for us to get
future suggestions.
I guess we got the answer to the
translation. Seems like there are quite
a few problem. Yeah. So, Ryan, the
enterprise is organizational.
the uh the user you can be a pro or or
free and on the organization you can be
either free team or enterprise I think
it's the three
um ones and then you can have on top of
that a GitHub enterprise that owns
several organizations where you can set
up
policies that that then like are applied
to all the organizations in that
enterprise
price. Yeah. So, there's different like
layers in that, but organizational
that's where you have your subscription
and that's where you have
um the enterprise
subscription and it's
licensed by
user by organization. That's probably
what your question actually is now.
In the Go workshop, there are still some
documentations like development
environments, the development process
missing. Any idea when they will
come?
Uh, no. But it sounds like something we
should we should
add. We have empty pages that says
coming soon or Yeah. Okay. Sorry about
that. I wasn't aware I wouldn't have had
time to do
that. But
yeah, we'll probably go through
that when we have
a time figure out what we can do about
those
things. Yes. The enterprise where there
are several orgs under one enterprise.
So it's safe to assume or OR or PC and
or PC can use the same license there
having one top level policy. I actually
don't know on that one. So yeah, better
better ask better better ask GitHub on
that or
um Yeah,
Uh we're currently seeing artifact URL
that have been changing. Is this by
design use case? We're using specific
artifact URL with the same go settings
JSON. So we changed them. But why are
they changing? The artifact URL is
changing.
Is it version disappearing glass or is
it like part of the host name that's
changing
maybe while you uh type something there
I can also so I've been working a little
bit around these artifacts recently and
there there a couple of changing there
were changes that being rolled out right
now uh so one of the things is in the
past you were able to connect to the
storage accounts directly
Um those URLs would be something like bc
artifacts.blo.s storage.net or something
like that. Uh and those will not work in
the future. Um in the future it'll be
like bc artifacts slash and then some
characters and then I actually forget
what the URL is exactly but it just
means that traffic will go through a
front door instead. Uh and this is part
of a a security push within within
Microsoft. So
uh this is something that's happening
now and the plan is at the end of June
we'll we'll stop you know the ability to
access the storage accounts directly and
so by that time all traffic should be
going through the front
doors. Uh so they have slightly
different URLs. I don't know if that's
maybe what you've
noticed. Yeah, we can get back to this
one.
Otherwise, just to confirm, once BC
container helper is deprecated, will
Microsoft replace or modify the
underlying tooling used in ALGO for
GitHub workflows or is algo already
fully independent of BC container
helper? It is definitely not. we have a
still have a bunch of work left to make
a go independent of container
helper. So I think that is kind of the
first thing we'll look at uh to see what
functionality a go needs from bc
container helper and extract that and
then you know we'll also take a look at
what else needs to be taken out of
container helper before we're fully
ready to deprecate it.
But there will be modifications coming
to you though.
I think it's safe to say that the
modifications in ALGO will probably I
mean you probably won't notice them in a
lot of
cases things will just happen and
suddenly your DevOps pipelines and
everything will be running independent
of BC container helper whereas if people
have written their own they'll be like
yeah they'll get
the they'll run into problems at some
point in time when container helper no
longer works.
Yeah. So last that change actually there
was
several several versions of that because
we the azure edge.net net is the old
um old what's it called? Front door CDN
CDN content delivery network that we
were using and we had to change that to
front door instead meaning that the
other URLs were now in play. Uh
typically BC container hover would
translate the top one to the lower one
and just automatically work. So if you
had of the other one it would still
work. I would expect that still to be
the case, but if not, I mean, yeah, the
get BC artifact UL will always return
the one that that you can use and should
check for translations would be truly
awesome.
Sounds like something we should work on.
But
since nearing the end,
has done an amazing effort with Algo Go.
With him leaving, how is the allocation
of resources from Microsoft managed?
Will the team work part-time on ALGO or
is a full-time project? We as a partner
are looking into investing in moving
from ADO to ALGO and we fear that the
project will not get the same amount of
love in the future. Any thoughts on
this?
I mean,
so in the past two years, we've been
three people working on Ago. Uh, Freddy,
me, Alexander, and Maria. Now, we just
got another person working on Algo as
well,
Sebastian. And, uh, yeah, even though
Freddy is leaving, we will be continuing
to work on Ago.
Um, yeah, I don't know how much I'm I'm
not really a I can't a manager or
anything. I can't really speak to how we
allocate time within Microsoft, but
uh I uh pretty confident we'll we'll
keep working on on it'll go uh a
significant
amount. And again, there's uh if you go
to Yammer under Microsoft announcements,
there is a statement from uh Dimmitri
from Microsoft uh basically also stating
that we're not defunding our efforts
into the go.
If I may chip in a little bit, I know
Freddy is leaving a lot of big shoes to
fill, but we'll try our best to kind of
match what he provided for the
community. It's
uh at some point Freddy mentioned like
don't worry for me leaving, worry for
yourself. But and now I actually started
feeling this because Freddy does have a
lot of connections and uh maybe a lot of
you like know know him personally and um
have built like this connection over
like
years and obviously we cannot match this
right here right now but we'll try. I
think we'll see our faces more often on
conferences and we'll try to stay active
as much as possible on GitHub replying
to your questions and trying to solve
your issues
etc. It is a bit of a shock but
uh life's life.
Let me also add
one sentence to that one.
Um, so I'm not dead, right? Um, and I
need to find find a way to like make a
living as well. So, um, I'm not applying
for a job at anybody any anywhere. What
I'm going to do is I'm going to start my
own business and figure out how I can I
can manage life, work, and whatever
experiences I want to have over the next
time. And it might be that that I'll be
visible in the community and doing
suggestions and doing stuff there. It
might be other things I have no idea
yet. First of all, I'm going to have
some some time off and then figure out
exactly how these things are going to
play out afterwards. So maybe I mean
maybe I'll I'll still do work on a go
just as a as
a somebody from outside of Microsoft and
hoping that they'll like accept my PRs
or whatever. I don't know. Let's see.
Obviously I need to earn some money as
well. I can't do everything for free
like I've done before. But uh let's
figure out what what happens.
a lot of love for
Freddy. Well
deserved. Is there already a Microsoft
manager who will take over the
responsibility for
ALGO? Um so Elgo will fall under and I
mean has fallen under the engineering
systems team which is the team I work on
Maria work on Yonas on the call is my
manager. So I guess the question the
answer here would be Yonas who's on the
call here he is the Microsoft manager
who will take over the responsibility of
algo.
Yeah, not even take over really. I mean,
it's been under it's been under our team
for a couple of years, but Fred has
still been the
one coming up with a lot of the stuff
we've been
doing. But now it lands on our team
engineering systems fully.
Any more questions here at the
end? Give it a few more minutes and then
otherwise
we'll see you next month I guess. Is
there off stars next month as well? I
guess. Yeah, I think July and December
were the only months we decided to
skip. So, it's either now or in a month
or on GitHub. Of
course, you can always reach us on in
the discussion tab on ALGO. There's also
a questions uh tab. So, you know, if you
run into questions along the way, you
can also ask them there. So, it's not
like we'll be off the face of the earth
for the next month. we'll be
here but not on this call. So if you
have any more questions, you have a
couple more
minutes or any more love for Freddy.
That's
also
welcomed. I got a lot of love on
LinkedIn when I posted the the news. I
mean, I've never seen I didn't see that
coming.
Like, I think it's 5,500 likes.
So,
600 messages still coming in. So,
The problem
is okay. Could we Yes. Let's wrap up. Um
yeah, thank you very much for joining.
We'll be here next month
and
yeah, see you.